JOHN LAZZARO

Web: http://goo.gl/OUd4tN Email: john.lazzaro@gmail.com

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

RTP-MIDI (2000-2011). Created a networking protocol that Apple has incorporated into the iOS and OS X operating systems. As part of the effort, I wrote the research grant the funded its development, and led its standardization effort in the IETF (culminating in RFC 6295).

Silicon Audition (1986-1998). Participated in the design of 14 analog VLSI circuits that emulated aspects of neurobiological auditory, visual, and cardiovascular sensory processing. Publications describing these chips have been referenced over 1400 times.

Teaching (2004-2014). Four semesters as the instructor of record for the undergraduate computer architecture class at UC Berkeley (CS 152), and a fifth semester co-teaching the class with the legendary David A. Patterson.

EDA Software (1985-2014). Wrote an interactive analog circuit simulator that was used for research and teaching at Caltech in the 1980s, and maintained a free software distribution based on these tools.

NIPS (1993-1999). Helped to put on the Neural Information Processing Systems conference, serving as Treasurer (1995), Tutorials Chair (1996), and as a program committee member (1993, 1994, 1999).

TIMELINE

Associate Research Specialist (1993–2014)

Lecturer (2004–2006, 2014)

Visiting Postdoctoral Computer Scientist (1991–1993)

University of California at Berkeley, Computer Science Division. Supervisor: John Wawrzynek.

Visiting Associate (1994-1997)

California Institute of Technology. Host: Carver Mead.

Research Assistant Professor (1990-1991)

University of Colorado at Boulder, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering.

Education

Ph.D. (June 1990) and M.S. (June 1986) in Computer Science.

California Institute of Technology (Advisor: Carver Mead).

B.S. Electrical Engineering and B.S. Computer Science (1984).

Moore School of Electrical Engineering, University of Pennsylvania.